Finding Aid for Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration (University of Michigan) Records and Illustrations
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration (University of Michigan) Records and Illustrations
1902-1991
1950-1985
University of Michigan. Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration.
0627 Bimu 2
This record group contains original artwork, administrative materials, and audiovisual materials produced by the University of Michigan Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration. The records represent the work of approximately 35 medical illustrators spanning the years 1902-1991. With circa 670 illustrations, the material documents the work of the faculty of the program and other prominent illustrators.
8 linear feet in 21 boxes
4 film reels 16 mm
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (donor # 9244 ) was received from the unit on August 2, 2002.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration was formally established at the University of Michigan in 1964, and conferred degrees on a small number of individuals annually beginning in 1966. The program was interdepartmental, offered jointly by the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies, the Medical School, and the School of Art. The Medical School provided space and budget for the program, and degrees were awarded by the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies in consultation with the School of Art.
The program's faculty resided either in the Medical School, the School of Art, or both. As such, the goals of the program were drawn from a combination of the objectives from each of the sponsoring institutions. The stated mission of the program was to "...continue graduating small numbers of highly skilled and versatile medical illustrators" (Box 1, Application for Accreditation Self-Evaluation Report, 1989, page 7). To this end, the students in the program were expected to have a strong background in the biological sciences, gain exposure to all areas of the biocommunication field in the course of the program, and master the skills needed to become "competent medical illustrators" (Box 1, Application for Accreditation Self-Evaluation Report, 1989, page 7). Coursework included such diverse topics as "anatomy, pathology, anatomical sketching, medical and scientific drawing techniques, surgical drawing, endoscopic drawing, advertising art and design, television graphics, museum methods, exhibit design, charts and graphs, and medical sculpture and prosthetics" (Box 1, Articles pertaining to UM program, 1956-1990, The Reporter Vol. 1, No. 2).
Although the program was founded in 1964 by Professor Gerald P. Hodge, who first came to the university in 1955, medical illustrators have been affiliated with the university since the early 20th century. Some of the earliest medical illustrators at the university include Emily S. Perry and Jeannette Young.
Medical illustrations were used in professional journals, medical texts, exhibits, and as teaching aids in lectures and on television. These illustrations were valued over photography because the artists could both delete "superfluous and confusing" material from a given view, and produce "schematic and diagrammatic" pictures (Box 1, Articles pertaining to UM program, 1956-1990, Visual Medicine Vol. 2, No. 3).
After all graduate programs and areas of emphasis were combined into a single, three-year MFA degree program in the School of Art & Design in the fall of 2003, the final class of the Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration graduated in the spring of 2004 and the program was discontinued.
The records of the Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration date from circa 1902 to 1991 and measure 8 linear feet plus 13 oversized boxes. The records are arranged in to two basic categories: 2 general series concerning program administration, and 15 series related to specific illustrators. The 17 series are as follows: General/Background, Gerald P. Hodge Illustrations, Alfred P. Teoli Illustrations, Evelyn Erickson Sullivan Illustrations, Max Brödel Illustrations, Emily Perry Illustrations, Elton E. Hoff Illustrations, Ralph Sweet Illustrations, Jeanette Young Illustrations, Neil Hardy Illustrations, J. McLaughlin Illustrations, Mary Lou Cummings Illustrations, Rictor S. Lew Illustrations, Grant S. Lashbrook Illustrations, Stephen G. Gilbert Illustrations, Miscellaneous Illustrations, and Audiovisual Materials. A small selection of illustrations displaying a variety of artists' work, techniques, and subjects has been digitized. The materials in each artist's series are predominantly arranged as received from the donor.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration.; Medical illustration--Study and teaching.; Surgery--United States.; Hodge, Gerald P.; Illustrators--United States.; Medical illustrators--United States--History.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Medical illustrations.; Anatomy.; Human body.; Surgery.
Contributors:
Hodge, Gerald P.; Brödel, Max, 1870-1941.; Sweet, Ralph, 1892-1961.; Teoli, Alfred.; Perry, Emily S.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Videotapes.; Photographs.
- General/Background
  - Articles pertaining to medical illustration, 1950-1985 (Box 1)
  - Articles pertaining to UM program, 1956-1990 (Box 1)
  - Articles pertaining to specific illustrators, 1960-1988 (Box 1)
  - Profession of Medical Art (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Final Report of the Review Committee on the Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Application for Accreditation Self-Evaluation Report, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Reprints I, 1912-1978 (Box 1)
  - Reprints II, 1911-1975 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1985 (Box 1)
  - Student Papers (Box 1)
  - Student Research, 1978 (Box 1)
- Gerald P. Hodge Illustrations
  The Gerald P. Hodge Illustrations series contains 289 illustrations by Prof. Gerald P. Hodge (emeritus). Hodge acted as director of the Medical and Biological Illustration program from 1964-1986. He was noted for his technique with pen-and-ink drawings, receiving the Russell Drake Award from the Association of Medical Illustrators in 1979.
  - Dermis Fat Graft, Orbital Cavity (Fig. 3 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Ted Wojno, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Dermis Fat Graft, Orbital Cavity (Fig. 2 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Dermis Fat Graft, Orbital Cavity (Fig. 1 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Concept of Vascular Headache, 1959; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Russell N. DeJong, Department: Neurology, University of Michigan Medical Center)
  - Trigeminal Rhizotomy: The Temporal Approach, 1964; Technique: India Ink on Scratch Board, #1000 Gillott (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Edward A. Kahn)
  - Surgery for Removal of Rectum (Fig. 1 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Thomas Dent, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Surgery for Removal of Rectum (Fig. 2 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Surgery for Removal of Rectum (Fig. 3 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Surgery for Removal of Rectum (Fig. 4 of 4), 1984; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Transrenal Excision of Sessile Rectal Polyps, Fig. 1, 1974; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. William Olsen, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Pancreatectomy, 1973; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Charles Frey, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Splenorenal Shunt, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Charles G. Child, III, and Jeremiah G. Turcotte, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Dissection of the Hepatoduodenal Ligament (Overlying lymphatics are divided and ligated), 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - Pancreatectomy (some revisions on those dated 1962), 1973; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - The Pancreas and Spleen, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Inoperative Portography and Splenoportography, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - Techniques of Portal Decompression (Fig. 8), 1962; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. George D. Zuidema, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. End-to-Side Choledochojejunostomy, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Charles G. Child, III, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Superior Mesenteric/Inferior Vena Caval Shunt (dog) fig. 3 of 3, 1977; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 2)
  - Superior Mesenteric/Inferior Vena Caval Shunt and Subtotal Gastrectomy (dog) fig. 2 of 3, 1977; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1970; Technique: India Ink on Illustration board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Henry Ranson, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - The Continuing Development of the Technique of Thyroidectomy, undated (Box 2)
  - Surgical Procedure for Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm. Method of flushing clot and debris from peripheral vessels and graft: A, Clamp removed from common ilian artery following completion of anastomosis; B, Aorta clamp released; C, Clamp applied to unastomosed limb; D, Completion of all anastomoses, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. John L. Ochsner, Department: The Ochsner Clinic, New Orleans, LA)
  - Normal Pancreaticodoudenal Venous Drainage (dog), 1977; Technique: India Ink on Line Kote (Box 2)
  - Technique for Transrectal Removal of Villous Tumor Plate II, 1974; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. William R. Olsen, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Surgical Procedure for Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Charles Claude Guthrie, M.D., Ph.D., 1880-1963; 1978; Technique: India Ink on Bristol board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. James C. Stanley, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Thyroid Series, 1967; Technique: Pen & Ink (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Norman Thompson, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Pancreatectomy (some revisions on those dated 1962), 1973; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - Side-to-Side Portacaval Shunt, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - Benign Rectal Polyps. (A) Large pedunculated polyp. (B) Small Sessile polyps (Drawing 1 of 4), 1965; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Henry Ransom, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Multiple Polyposis of the Colon and Rectum (Drawing 2 of 4), 1965; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. End-to-Side Pancreaticojejunostomy and End-to-End Choledochojejunostomy, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Abdominal Closure Employing Buried Through-and-Through Sutures, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Exploration of the Base of Mesacolon, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Division of Stomach, Pancreas, and Common Hepatic Duct, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Extent of Pancreaticoduodenectomy, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Pancreatectomy (some revisions on those dated 1962), 1973; Technique: India Ink on Ross Scratch Board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Mobilization of the Duodenum and Head of Pancreas, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Resected Specimen of Rectum Showing Small Sessile Carcinoma of Rectal Ampulla (Combined Abdominoperineal Resection), 1965; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Henry K. Ransom, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. End-to-Side Implantation of a Normal Common Duct into the Jejunum, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Vena Caval-Superior Mesenteric Shunt, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Techniques of Portal Decompression 1963 modified in 1969, Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Subtotal Pancreatectomy. Gastroenteric Reconstruction Completed by Antecolic Gastrojejunostomy, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Chronic Fibrocalcific Pancreatitis, 1962; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Charles G. Child, III, and Jeremiah Turcotte, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan)
  - Techniques of Portal Decompression, 1963; Technique: India Ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Open drop ether technique, undated (Box 2)
  - Sagittal View of Plexus Showing Sacral Nerve Plexus, circa 1958; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross stipple board #00 (Box 2)
  - Use of rectal thiopental, undated; Technique: Unknown (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1969; Technique: Unknown (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Lapides, Department: Urology)
  - Morphologic Variations of Aortic Aneurysms A, fusiform. B, saccular. C, Dissecting, 1969; Technique: Gillott #1000 pen and India ink on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
  - Untitled, circa 1967 (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Cameron Haight, Department: Thoracic Surgery)
  - X-Ray Tracing--Newborn, undated (Box 2)
    (Department: Thoracic Surgery)
  - The Barriers to Auscultation, undated (Box 2)
  - Ruptured chordae tendineae or papillary muscle, undated (Box 2)
  - Annuloplasty technique, undated (Box 2)
  - Premaxillary setback, undated (Box 2)
    (Department: Plastic Surgery)
  - Ear, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Sternocleidomastoid muscle transplant to masseter area, 1970 (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. T. Hudak, Department: Plastic Surgery)
  - Untitled, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Neck, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled Equipment, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Head, undated (Box 2)
  - Face, undated (Box 2)
  - Skin Graft on leg, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2)
  - Skin Graft on heel, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Skin Graft, dental, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Thickness of Skin Graft, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Scalp, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Replacement of biceps, 1982 (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Thomas L. Stevenson, Department: Plastic Surgery)
  - Head, undated (Box 2)
  - Examples of the three types of condylar surface irregularities, 1965; Technique: India ink and Gillotte #1000 pen on Ross scratch board (Box 2)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Reed O. Dingman, Department: Plastic Surgery)
  - Curved preauricular incision used for approach to the temporomandibular joint. (2 of 4 drawings), 1965; Technique: India ink on Gillotte #1000 pen on Ross scratch board (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Reed O. Dingman, Department: Plastic Surgery, University of Michigan Medical Center)
  - Incision in the parotideomasseteric fascia which lies over the joint capsule (2 of 4 drawings), 1965; Technique: India ink on Gillotte #1000 pen on Ross scratch board (Box 3)
  - Incisions are made through the joint capsule (4 of 4 drawings), 1965; Technique: India ink on Gillotte #1000 pen on Ross scratch board (Box 3)
  - Types of wedge incisions or, 1964; 1965 (Box 3)
  - Skin Tapes, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Normal right typmpanic membrane, undated (Box 3)
    (Department: Otorhinolar)
  - Continuous over and over, undated (Box 3)
  - Simple, undated (Box 3)
  - Vertical mattress, undated (Box 3)
  - Horizontal mattress, undated (Box 3)
  - Half-buried horizontal mattress, undated (Box 3)
  - Subcuticular continuous, undated (Box 3)
  - Type I tympanoplasty (myringoplasty), undated (Box 3)
    (Department: Otoprhinolar)
  - Otosclerosis, undated (Box 3)
  - Aspirating tip used to withdraw fluid or mucus from middle ear, undated (Box 3)
  - Collateral ligament, Accessory collateral ligament, Volar Plate, 1969 (Box 3)
    (Department: Orthopedic)
  - Untitled, 1961 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Reilly, Department: Orthopedic)
  - Techniques of Portal Decompression, 1963; Technique: India Ink on scratch board (Box 3)
  - Gallstone and cross-section of gallstone, undated (Box 3)
    (Department: Urology)
  - Postoperative sacro-coccyggeal teratoma, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Urethro-vaginal fistula, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Finea Circinata, undated (Box 3)
  - Rib, undated; Technique: Unknown, poss. Carbon dust (Box 3)
  - Hodge copy of a Brödel, 1947; Technique: Unknown, poss. Carbon dust (Box 3)
  - Carcinoma of Breast, 1950; Technique: Water color, colored pencils and opaque white (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Everett D. Sugarbaker, Department: Sugarbaker Tumor Clinic, Jefferson City, Missouri)
  - Trigeminal Rhizotomy, 1964; Technique: Sepia toned photographs of original drawing, water color (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Edward A. Kahn, Department: Neurosurgery)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Sepia toned photographs of original drawing, water color added (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Sepia toned photographs of original drawing, water color added (Box 3)
    (Department: Neurosurgery)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Sepia toned photographs of original drawing, water color added (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated; Technique: Sepia toned photographs of original drawing, water color added (Box 3)
  - Abbess and Hemorrhage of the Brain, circa 1958; Technique: Airbrush, watercolor, gouache (Box 3)
  - Essential Iris Atrophy, circa 1961; Technique: Preliminary sketch and notes for preceding drawing (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Douglas A. Liddicott and Harold F. Falls, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - The most common type of central intermesenteric anastomosis between the superior and inferior arterial systems, 1956; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross stipple board #00 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Gail H. William, Department: Surgery, University of Michigan Medical Center)
  - Exposure for adenoma of superior parathyroid, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 1 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 2 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 3 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 4 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 4, 1973 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. W. R. Olsen, Norman W. Thompson and G. Hoffman, Department: Surgery)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 5 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 6 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 7 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Thyroidectomy No. 8 of 8, 1970; Technique: 3B carbon dust, H and HH carbon pencils, and 9H graphite pencil on video paper (Box 3)
  - Dilatation of branches of external carotid artery--the cause of the headache phase of migraine, 1959; Technique: Airbrush and carbon dust on Ross stipple board #1 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Russell N. DeJong, Department: Neurology, University of Michigan)
  - Tension and spasm of scalp and neck muscles responsible for residual head and neck pain, 1959; Technique: Airbrush and carbon dust on Ross stipple board #1 (Box 3)
  - Anterior Approach for Intradural Tumor, 1969; Technique: H Carbon dust of Video Paper (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Richard Schneider, Department: Neurosurgery, University of Michigan)
  - Corneal Suturing, 1954 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. George Haik, Department: Ophthalmology, Louisiana State University School of Medicine
  - Anatomy of the Eye (1 of 2), 1959; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross stipple board #00 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. F. Bruce Fralick, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Anatomy of the Eye (2 of 2), 1959; Technique: Carbon dust on Ross stipple board #00 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Superior vena cava, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, circa 1961 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1961 (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Sloan)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Joe D. Morris, Department: Thoracic Surgery, University Hospital)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3)
  - Figure 9 (part I), undated (Box 3)
  - Removal of calcification (top view), undated (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3)
  - A Maneuver for Control of Hemorrhage during Repair of the Toru Atrium, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Catheter from left ureter placed in spinal cord at L2-L3 level, undated (Box 3)
  - 12 unidentified illustrations (Box 3)
  - Skull, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal Septum (bony and cartilaginous skeleton), undated (Box 4)
  - Nerves of the Lateral Wall of the Right Nasal Cavity, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal Septum (mucous membrane), undated (Box 4)
  - Osteology (lateral wall of right nasal fossa), undated (Box 4)
  - Skull, undated (Box 4)
  - Nerves-Nasal Septum, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Lateral Wall of Right Nasal Cavity (portions of nasal conchae removed), undated (Box 4)
  - Lateral Wall of Right Nasal Cavity, undated (Box 4)
  - Arteries of the Lateral Wall of the Right Nasal Cavity, undated (Box 4)
  - Arteries of the Nasal Septum, undated (Box 4)
  - Lateral Wall of Right Nasal Cavity (portions of nasal conchae removed), undated (Box 4)
  - Arteries of the Lateral Wall of the Right Nasal Cavity, undated (Box 4)
  - Nose, undated (Box 4)
  - Lateral Wall of Right Nasal Cavity, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal Septum (Mucous membrane), undated (Box 4)
  - Osteology-Lateral wall of the right front fossa, undated (Box 4)
  - Plate B Osteology, undated (Box 4)
  - Cartilage (adapted from dissected nose), undated (Box 4)
  - Topography of Nose, undated (Box 4)
  - Thoracic: G. Hodge for Dr. Cameron Hight (U of M Surgeon) (Box 4)
  - Laryngeal prominence, undated (Box 4)
  - Posterior Thyroid Capsule and residual thyroid g, undated (Box 4)
  - Ophthalmology: Slit Lamp Sketches (Box 4)
  - Ophthalmology (Prism) (Box 4)
  - Thoracic: G. Hodge for Dr. Cameron Haight (U of M Surgeon) (Box 4)
  - Eye, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Untitled sketch, undated (Box 4)
  - Muscles-Arteries, circa 1972 (Box 4)
  - Nasal surgery, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal surgery, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal surgery, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal surgery, undated (Box 4)
  - Nasal surgery, undated (Box 4)